Connecting a festival with
a planet in the universe is the Mid-Autumn Festival among Chinese festivals,
so the Mid-Autumn Festival is also called the Moon Festival. From the moon
to the Mid-Autumn Festival, the moon is bright and the moon shines brightly throughout the
year
.
Thousands of people enjoy poetry together. The bright moon in the
sky
and the
feelings of
the world people The stories
and cultural meanings surrounding the
special celestial phenomenon of the Mid-Autumn Festival and the bright moon have formed the unique emotional expressions of the Chinese people. Here comes the
three days before the Mid-Autumn Festival,
in
the yard
of Liu Cuixiang’s home in Zhaoyu Ancient City, Qi County,
Shanxi
Start making mooncakes, and the
neighbors
come to help in
twos
and threes.
This is not only to add hands to the work , but also
a harmonious atmosphere in the neighborhood. We used to be the old people
when
we
were young . On the
kang
, my
lord
sits there and we watch from the sidelines. Anyway, sometimes when there is trouble, I want to do it. My
lord won’t let us do it , and then we will do it ourselves when we grow up
. According to the custom handed down from the ancestors, the Mid-Autumn Festival is made by
hand
.
In Shanxi, the Mid-Autumn Festival is generally called the 15th day of the eighth month. It
is a folk festival second only to the Spring Festival.
Shanxi moon cakes are very particular about the fillings, including
red dates
, walnuts,
beans, persimmons
,
and Guofu brown sugar. There are more than 10 kinds of
meanings in total. The meaning of perfection is that the shape of
moon cakes is mainly round, and there are also gourd-shaped,
peach -shaped or crescent-shaped, crescent-
shaped small moon cakes in the shape of rabbits. They are special gifts for children. They are derived from the jade rabbit in the middle of the moon.
I hope they will be able to Zen public folding cabinets
in the future and entrust adults. Our best wishes. In the rural areas of
Shanxi , the wooden molds for making moon cakes have the most local characteristics. They are
called moon cake molds . The exquisitely carved moon cake molds were
treasures loved by every household in the past. They were all proud of having a few good molds. The
mold making is the jujube wood mooncake mold handed down from the ancestors. It can be said that it is made of high
-quality materials
. Every family
also makes a wax mooncake to worship
the moon . The last procedure of
making mooncakes is also the most important part of making mooncakes.
Not only should the heat be appropriate, but also
the color of the baked mooncakes should be uniform
. The baked mooncakes should have a crispy texture after cooling.
This process is usually completed by the hostess at home. People in
Shanxi celebrate the Mid-Autumn Festival in
every household .
In addition to eating at home, relatives
and friends also have to exchange with each other.
Whose craftsmanship is better can be seen at
a glance
. This simple philosophy of the Chinese has
become a kind of inheritance in every
festival . Eating mooncakes means Mid-Autumn Festival. The footsteps have arrived.
The modern way of life has changed
the way of crossing the streets of many city people
from time to time .
In many places, Mid-Autumn Mooncakes have to be bought in the market. In front of Changfa Cake Shop on Lindun Road, Pingjiang District,
Suzhou City, there is a queue early in the morning of the Mid-Autumn Festival.
There was a long queue selling a kind of fresh meat mooncakes
. Suzhou’s fresh meat mooncakes
are an indispensable delicacy
for people here to celebrate the Mid-Autumn Festival. The rare delicacy
is baked and sold right away. It is
fragrant and
only sold once a year
. Mooncakes
are crispy on the outside and tender on the inside. A
bite of
fresh meat
mooncakes is the unique taste of Suzhou people about the Mid-Autumn Festival
. Smell it,
smell it, smell the big meat stuffing
, look at
it The soup is flowing there.
Yes,
yes, is
this moon cake
delicious
? Yes, it is delicious
. We still have good comrades . We are going to line up.
In traditional Chinese festivals, each festival has specific customs.
Eat dumplings and rice cakes during the Spring Festival.
Lantern Festival Eat glutinous rice balls, eat rice dumplings at the
Dragon Boat
Festival, eat Chongyang cakes at the Double Ninth Festival, and eat mooncakes at the
Mid-
Autumn Festival .
Tears stained with gold
Because
Su Shi was famous,
this poem was widely spread.
Gradually ,
the name of moon cake became the patent of this kind of cake.
Su Shi not only
fixed the name of the food in
the specific festival of Mid-Autumn Festival, but
also wrote the artistic conception of moon cake and Mid-Autumn Festival together.
In the taste of longing, longing for reunion and blessings,
one side nourishes the other side, and people in
different places have different tastes,
so Mid-Autumn moon cakes have also evolved into Cantonese-style mooncakes,
Soviet
-style mooncakes
, Beijing-style mooncakes, Chaozhou -style mooncakes, etc. Dozens of mooncakes are named after places. Mooncakes are in
the largest Chinatown in the western United States. On the
eve of the Mid-Autumn Festival,
buying
mooncakes to celebrate the Mid-Autumn Festival
is a habit
that the local Chinese have never changed
. For example
, if you eat lotus paste bean paste
, it’s Cantonese.
If you eat jujube pears and bean paste
, it’s from the north . If you eat pineapple and your puff pastry
, it’s from Taiwan.
In the earliest
days, the mooncake shop operated by Chen Yongxing
imported mooncakes from Guangdong.
In order to meet the needs of customers,
he began to make mooncakes by himself. Before he
knew
it , he had been in the United States for decades.
Lah , we all miss growing up in China and eating food, so we try our best to give it a chance
. Come
and I will introduce some friends to eat here
. These are our Chinese
fishermen who come here. It is a
festival every year . Of course, they are moon cakes
, as if they are members of our team.
There is bean paste, bean paste, bean paste, bean paste,
oh bean paste. Our lord, they like to eat,
because
each person eats,
um, most of the
guests
are basically Chinese,
because
they know that you really like to give away Bowl stickers 㗎
La , there are some Westerners from time to time,
but they don’t buy as much as us Chinese. It’s
OK, not bad.
I
place orders like this every year.
Oh, around, we want Send it away
Let
’s send a follow
, send it from all over Hawaii. On the night of the
full moon , every mooncake is a kind of nostalgia. The custom of Mid
-Autumn Festival mooncakes is not only a ritual , but also a psychological need of the Chinese nation.
In San Francisco, USA The
mooncake shop in Chinatown, Chen Yongxing is about to end the busiest season of the year.
The famous violin maker Mr. Cao Shukun and his family in San Francisco have
started their Mid-
Autumn Festival
. Grandmother, there is a grandson who
told you to bury you
, grandson is here, grandma, grandma, mid-autumn festival, the moon rises above
the sea
, the end of the world is at this time,
even
though Sanfan City There is a 16-hour time difference with Guangzhou,
which cannot block the holiday blessings from relatives
Okay, take it
with me,
okay,
these are two
, ah, this is a pair, this is a pair,
I took this to worship the moon, this
, this, this, what is
that called, I took one,
yes,
one One, Ms. Xia Meizhen from
Yangzhou ,
came to the street market early in the morning on the 15th day of the eighth lunar month to carefully select various foods
for tonight’s moon sacrifice.
Pomegranate is a blessing for having more children. People in the
past
just wanted more children. I will be blessed
with persimmons,
persimmons, everything goes well.
Today, we have basically bought them in place.
China has a vast territory
. The ingredients used for worshiping the moon in various places
are selected according to local specialties. The
Mid-Autumn Festival is the autumn harvest season.
The ancient autumn festival The moon is on the day of the autumnal equinox, which means
offering sacrifices to the moon
and celebrating the harvest.
People share the joy of the harvest and
show the fruits of autumn labor to the
moon
. Is this pancake ready?
Well , it’s a cake for
descendants and grandchildren.
I have it for Fei Yue tonight . Do you
know about descendants’ cakes? My descendants’ cakes are
descendants’ and grandchildren’s cakes,
and they
are not high. One
floor is higher than the first floor. There are 9 floors in
total . I come to live in your house every year
.
Yes , yes, yes.
Thank you. The sesame candied biscuits I bought
in Anjia Alley
are a necessity for half a month tonight. In the
past , people in Yangzhou celebrated the Mid-Autumn Festival. Every household used a
small stove to make their own biscuits. The whole family gathered around the small stove and waited for the sesame candied biscuits to be baked. The
children rushed to
eat and bit down.
The hot sweetness is overflowing on the tip of the tongue.
It is the eternal taste of Mid-Autumn Festival in the children’s memory. There is
no stuffing.
Oh , it’s delicious.
Oh, it
’s awesome . When Ms. Xia Meizhen from Yangzhou
was making various preparations for the Mid-Autumn Festival, she was
also in Sucheng, another ancient city in Jiangsu.
Suzhou has
opened the Mid-Autumn Festival for
Suzhou people in another way. The Beijing-Hangzhou Grand Canal passes through the city,
leaving behind endless legends. When you
come to Suzhou
, in addition to the famous Jiangnan gardens in Suzhou, you
have to mention Tiger Hill, a geomantic treasure in the ancient city of Suzhou. Huqiu Mountain Scenic Area has a history of
more than 2,500 years. It is
known as the first scenic spot in Wuzhong
. The origin of Huqiu and Mid-Autumn Festival
is because of an essay written by Ming Dynasty writer Zhang Dai.
Climbing high and seeing knowledge is like a wild goose falling down on the flat sandy clouds on
the river
. It can be imagined that during the
Ming and Qing Dynasties
, Suzhou citizens had the custom of listening to songs on the Tiger Hill
during the Mid-Autumn Festival .
Time flies.
Today ’s Tiger Hill continues this kind of prosperity and excitement.
According to the deep palace
The stone nods . The legend of the
white lotus blooming is still spreading among the mountains and rivers. It is full of spiritual energy and has
become a colorful stage play . The Yunyan tea, which was once rare,
stretches between square inches,
or rolls or
relaxes. The
bright moon comes to everyone’s life Between the Eyebrows and Hearts, the Huqiu
Music Festival
is a large-scale folk
spontaneous Kunqu opera gathering in Suzhou history.
Literati,
lyric masters
, professional artists, and
ordinary people
will spontaneously gather on the Tiger Hill on the night of the Mid-Autumn Festival .
Zhang Jue, who has practiced
Kunqu opera for many years, recites teachings and sings competitively . It has been a wish
of his for many years
to be able to
exhibit Kunqu opera at the Huqiu Opera Festival. The top-
dressing Baotou,
temple shadow flower shop, and
meticulous professional
artist's artistic creation have turned
into a spiritual force.
What I am singing today is the one
in the Peony Pavilion
. The special order is Du Liniang. In that dream, he was
looking for the garden he had been to and singing about the scenery in that garden.
Love,
keep ,
ah, ah
, the
moon reflects on the tiger hill, on the
rocks and under the pagoda,
singing a song of Peony Pavilion, the
lingering sound
is long Zhang Jue uses his own way
Realizing the date of the Mid-Autumn Festival,
with myself, Suzhou and Tiandi
, Kunqu
is known as the top of a hundred operas, and it has gone through desolation and prosperity
due to
the changes of the times
Selected items on the list As
the hometown of Kunqu opera, enjoy the
moon and listen to it,
gather together
with young and old Miji,
become a unique gathering scene of
Gusu Mid-Autumn Festival , listen to a Kunqu opera in the beautiful Jiangnan garden,
enjoy
a piece of Suzhou
Pingtan , it is the
Mid-Autumn Festival for Suzhou people
Another wonderful combination of the night
Suzhou
Pingtan
A drop of water that penetrates the years
Qianqian quality Gently plucks the tenderness on the string
Strands of thoughts weave a smooth thick
Bit of emotion brewed into intoxicating wine
Mingyue
Garden Kunqu Pingtan Mid -Autumn Festival Night What kind of comfortable state of mind would Suzhou people have?
Just when Suzhou people were
immersed in the elegance and
delicacy of Kunqu Opera and poverty
, the brothel organized by Ms. Xia Meizhen from Yangzhou started to
offer
tributes
. Now our 7 children offer tributes to the moon god.
Hexagonal bells The implication is dexterity and ingenuity. The
seedlings make us often meet good people
. The pomegranate symbolizes many children and blessings. The
apple is safe
and sound. The lotus root in the middle represents the prosperity of children and grandchildren. The
incense burns continuously. The
nine-layer sugar cake symbolizes the sweetness
of life. The moon palace cakes are shared by the world
, and the moon palace cakes are specially used to worship the moon god. In the eyes of Yangzhou people
, the Wuting Bridge of the Slender West Lake is the most desirable place to enjoy the moon.
The
Wuting Bridge is known as the most beautiful bridge in China and
is a masterpiece of ancient bridge architecture.
The place Ms.
Xia Meizhen chose for the Mid-Autumn Festival in
2018 is at Wuting Bridge. Worshiping the moon in
autumn
is a traditional folk custom ceremony in Yangzhou. As early as the Tang Dynasty,
Yangzhou
had a profound cultural atmosphere
. The ways of worshiping the moon include: Clothes and instrumentation
are compiled by Ms. Xia Meizhen after many years of visits
, expert research,
and combined with modern people's emotional changes towards the Mid-Autumn Festival
. Reunion
, blessing, and
advocating nature are
all in their gestures.
Yangzhou people's preservation and inheritance of the custom of worshiping the moon is
in a sense. The above
is a unique emotional expression of this city.
At the same time, Yangzhou is known as the moon city. I
found
a suitable interpretation. The poet Xu Ning of the Tang Dynasty said in Yangzhou that the
world
is three-pointed, and the moon night is two points. The rogue is Yangzhou .
The beauty of the moonlight night has a total of three points
, so
the beauty of
the moonlight night in Yangzhou City
occupies a full two points . It is the literati of the past dynasties
The reason
why I like to come to Yangzhou to enjoy the moon is that Yangzhou has thousands of poems and
songs about
chanting
the bright moon
. Fishing
branches
together, the
son asked Cao Cao
.
Flying in the blue clouds, the
immortal hangs down on two legs, the osmanthus tree is round, the white rabbit
is smashed into medicine, ask who to eat with. Up to now , Yangzhou city still retains a lot
of place names related to the moon, such as Mingyue Lake Mingyue Bridge, Wangyue Bridge, Lanyue Bridge, Deyue Bridge
, etc. They all silently talked about the peerless youth of Moon City, which won more room for imagination
for Yangzhou Moon City.
Therefore , it
is reasonable
for Yangzhou people to spend the Mid-Autumn Festival so beautifully and gracefully.
The moon in Yangzhou
is poetry, dream , history and culture.
The value contribution of traditional Chinese festivals
Shanxi people pay special attention to the reunion dinner on the evening of the Mid-Autumn Festival.
Now the round cakes on the Mid-Autumn Festival are also round, and the
moon cakes
are also round.
You can see his life. The
reunion dinner dumplings are the protagonists
, but the dumplings on the Mid-Autumn Festival are different from the usual Dumplings are different and round in
shape .
Chinese people use this kind of devotion to
bless
the touch that the full moon brings to people. A
round of Mid-Autumn
Moon
touches the hearts of countless Chinese children
and evokes a faint nostalgia in everyone's heart.
Nostalgia
is the shadow of a tree whirling in the yard,
it is the mother A wisp of Fanxiang in my hand
is the warm loess of my hometown, the heartbeat
in a silent night, the
spring breeze
is green again
, the south bank of the river is bright
, when will the moon shine on me,
no matter the past,
present
or future
, the Mid-Autumn Moon will illuminate everyone’s way home
Shame
on him
Yeah
, the old people in Lianfeng
Village, Dadong Town, Dapu County, Meizhou, Guangdong , thousands of kilometers away from Shanxi Province, choose the place
to worship and enjoy the
moon in their ancestral house of the Hakka people, the Tuweilou
Huaelou
, which is as
tall as a city wall.
Sifang , ancestors and ancestors wish the central government to go in the wind and rain,
and enjoy the well-being in the dragon house . A folk song widely circulated in the Meizhou area
expresses the deep love
of the Hakka people for thousands of years. Thousands of years ago, the
Hakka ancestors Difficult to move all the
way , the road is blue , the typical representative of Hakka dwellings, Wailongwu,
is the best witness.
In addition to being able to live in peace,
Hakka
Wailongwu also contains the meaning
of square circle, family and country harmony.
Beginning in the afternoon, the villagers
will put on new couplets and
hang lanterns in the surrounding houses. The festive
atmosphere is more obvious. As
night falls, the old man Lin Zhiming leads the villagers to start placing moon cakes
, peanuts, pomelo and other festive food and fruits.
This ceremony is called respecting the moonlight.
Every household prepares
their own food Standing together is
a kind of ritual
and also a strength.
Besides moon cakes,
pomelo is an indispensable food product for the Mid-Autumn Festival.
Meizhou is the hometown of pomelo in China,
and Hakka people eat pomelo. It also has a certain meaning.
Cutting pomelo is called sand pomelo
, which means to exorcise evil spirits.
In addition , the shape of grapefruit is big and round
, which also means reunion and happiness.
This year is not a new year cake. You
want to change this person. It’s not just observing this with silly eyes
. In the past, the way Hakkas celebrated the Mid-Autumn Festival was to face the moon
and rise
in the courtyard,
terrace
or in front of the house, but today’s moon worship
is more like a The group gathering
of the whole village is mostly the elderly and children.
It is said that many young people went out to work and failed to come back
. Because of this, old man Lin Zhiming insisted on organizing
the whole village to celebrate the festival together in the ancestral house when the moon is full in the Mid-Autumn Festival. The moon is full and people are
full .
Tuweilou carries the endless nostalgia of the Hakka people.
Mid-Autumn Moonlight Night
once again
brings together
loved ones and sublimates
love . The Tuweilou Mid-Autumn Festival reunion
shows another realm
of human relations .
Micro-carved vine-edge pottery and
brick carvings in Zhuzi Street, Chancheng District, Foshan, Guangdong
Wood carving , poetic
paper-cutting,
paper-painted porcelain,
embroidery
, etc. 12 kinds of intangible cultural
heritage handicrafts with Foshan characteristics
. Meet with tourists in
the Mid-Autumn Festival and imprint the Mid-Autumn Festival with a strong Lingnan flavor. The
74-year-old Hexin
is
the country of Foshan folk handicrafts and paper shops.
Inheritor of intangible cultural heritage transmission at the national level
Paper puff art is a representative item of national intangible cultural heritage
. The most unique part of the autumn scenery in Foshan.
Like the autumn scenery skills
, there are layers . Use the paper to read it and read the details first
. It’s not convenient to cut it if you know how to make a hair. On
the various molds that have been made,
glue the paper layer by layer with water, and use
paper to imitate various objects
, as well as traditional festivals and
autumn parades. Works
can come out. It’s just a shape.
Craftsmen use paper or chili as raw materials and
use a pair of skillful hands
to
make replicas of various objects in life that are difficult to distinguish between true and false
. They make chickens
and moon cakes. Basically, they are made of paper. But
for this case, I use wax
because the wax needs to fall off,
because the wax will be more moist
and transparent, and the wax is for those delicate things,
such joints
, which are easier to get out
. Clearly , the daughter of the old man Hexin is also learning the art
of papier- mâché . This craft is passed down in a family way. The production process seems simple
, but the art of crafting usually
reveals its essence in talent and time.
Mid -Autumn Festival
Moon cakes
are also
displayed in a unique way on this year’s Mid-Autumn Festival.
Zhang Hanquan , the intangible cultural heritage of Foshan City and the
inheritor of the Foshan Brick Carving
Project
, began to carve the Moon Palace and
Moon
Rabbit for his friends on the afternoon of the Mid-Autumn Festival. He
recorded the Mid-Autumn Festival with intangible cultural heritage crafts. A beautiful story.
Brick carving is a unique sculpture craft of Chinese architecture.
Brick carving is mainly used for exterior decoration of building parts. It is
integrated with the main building and
has a strong decorative effect . It is widely used in traditional buildings in Lingnan, Guangdong. The
production process of brick carving
is delicate and complicated.
Proofing: stamp
the design draft on the brick surface
or draw
the draft directly on the bricks; hacking:
use a chisel or a carving knife to roughly outline the outline of the picture ;
use a variety of tools to shovel , engrave, tone, etc. to describe the details and other procedures to complete the play.
Of course,
the most important thing It is the dedicated spirit
and artistic feeling of a professional carving artist.
Fortunately, I have selected this brick before. It’s good
for barbecue. It’s easy to choose. It’s mila
, and it’s very obedient.
I’ve selected
it. If you want, please pray pray
The hook machine, I can’t
turn it around.
I dropped it and placed it in an exhibition room.
Underground
, Master Zhang’s Moon Palace Moon
Rabbit was made just in time for the full moon on the Mid-Autumn Festival night.
It took 6 hours.
Zhuzi Street
used to be a famous commercial street in Foshan during the Ming and Qing Dynasties. Brick sculptures and
plaster sculptures
, blue brick walls of raised-foot buildings,
gabled Manchuria windows , Shiwan
Lingnan Wine Culture Museum, the perfect combination of
rice crown paintings
and intangible cultural heritage handicrafts
make the 2019 Mid-Autumn Festival for Foshan people Have taste and
culture .
China has a vast territory. People
living by the sea are
used to coming to the seaside on the night of the Mid-Autumn Festival. The sea and the
sky make this festival more artistic
. Zeng Songli from Haimen District, Shantou, Guangdong, entered a teahouse by the sea.
Chaoshan’s Kung Fu tea is famous Very big. Chaoshan people in
Guangdong like to drink tea
, and they also pay attention to drinking tea.
On weekdays
, family members rarely have the opportunity to get together.
During the Mid-Autumn Festival in 2019, the
children rushed back from other places to celebrate the festival
. Zeng Songli went out early in the morning to
buy fruits . A kind of pastry that must be eaten is
called Haimen cake.
This food is a small cake made of fresh glutinous rice
.
No one can say clearly what the relationship between this cake and the Mid-Autumn Festival is.
Maybe the round cake also means reunion.
Zeng Songli is still a local He is a paper-cutting expert. He
specially cuts a jade rabbit as a gift tonight. I see you go back to Nanjing
You can see that you are on the road. You have to
wait for two feet
. It’s long and
long
. It’s right,
um
, thank you,
oops ,
thank you
Thank you , ah
, ah, grandma’s house
is
close to the
wooden plank road not far away, and there are young people who come to Haimen from other places to work in the
cafe . Most
of the topics discussed
tonight
are related to the Mid-Autumn Festival. When I was a
child, my grandma spent the Mid-Autumn Festival with me there, admiring the
moon . I picked those pears and the special product of our hometown that I bought above, the
Huanxi pomelo
, and the special product of our hometown, that
kind of big gift cake. I will send it to the moon
first
, and we will eat it after sending the moon.
It ’s been so many years since I’ve been here.
Anyway , when I came to the Mid-Autumn Festival, I
took a video for my grandma and watched it. During the
Mid -Autumn Festival,
our custom there is to eat pears and mooncakes.
Well , it’s different from Chaoshan.
Come here to Chaoshan . At the
beach, you can enjoy the moon and
listen to the sound of the sea, but I still miss
the
scene when I was a child in my hometown.
Auspiciousness is that the story is different from history
, but it always adds more magnificence and
imagination to the history, which is enough for everyone to participate.
So In the age of believing in science, there should
also be charming stories
, magnificent imaginations and beautiful legends. The moon is full in the
sky , the
feelings of the
world , worshiping the moon and admiring the moon
. The mentality and
emotion
of the Chinese people are
vivid and natural under
the moonlight like water. Bow your
head
and think about your hometown and see the bright moon on the sea. The
sky is at this moment.
From ancient times to the present, the
Mid -Autumn Festival has been endowed with more meanings.
Chinese people put all their thoughts, nostalgia
and good wishes on the bright moon of the Mid-Autumn Festival. At
the same time , they are also tolerant, open-minded and kind to the Chinese people.
The tenacity of the national spirit is accurately expressed through
the full moon. The cultural significance and philosophical thoughts of the
Mid-Autumn Festival formed during thousands of years of civilization inheritance are
not only a time period mark , but also belong to all mankind. When will the
bright moon
come? Ask about the wine.
Wow , what a big moon
!